campuscruiser.com 2018-07-05

# Privacy | Campuscruiser

**Protecting Our Users’ Privacy**

Protecting the users’ privacy is Campuscruiser’s top concern. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices, and applies to campuscruiser.com, prod.campuscruiser.com, mobile versions, and mobile apps.

**GDPR**

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a data protection and privacy regulation put forth by the European Union (EU) law which protects all individuals within the EU and the European Economic Area (EAA). This includes export of Personal Identifying Information (PII) outside the EU and EAA.

PII is any data that may identify you personally. Examples of data we may store in our system include, but are not limited to name, address, telephone number, and IP address. The GDPR was implemented to give individuals control over this personal data. Basically the regulation applies if the data controller (your school who may collect data from EU residents), or processor (Campuscruiser processes data on behalf of your school), or a person (whose data has been collected) is based in the EU. Sometimes this regulation also applies to organizations based outside the EU if they collect or process personal data of individuals located inside the EU.

By submitting personal information through any Campuscruiser site, you expressly consent to the processing of your personal information in the United States.

**User Data**

Campuscruiser may collect PII regarding individuals which is specifically and knowingly provided by the individual user or the college they attend. Under no circumstances will user’s personal information be given to any other party (except the college they attend) unless otherwise stated at the time of collection or as required by law. We will never share your e-mail address with other third parties without your prior opt-in.

**Collected Information (from you, your school, or the Campuscruiser system)**

Some examples:

  1. First and Last Name
  2. Address (home, business, e-mail)
  3. Title
  4. Company Name
  5. Login/Password
  6. IP Address
  7. Device Type
  8. Domain
  9. How you are using our system
  10. Date/Time Stamp (per visit via Cookies)
  11. Information collected via survey

Because each user has access to a set of Personal Tools, some content may be stored that may include PII. This may also be true if the user uploads files or participates in discussion topics within communities on the Campuscruiser site.

Campuscruiser utilizes a widely used tool called Cookies which sends a small piece of data to the user’s computer when visiting a Campuscruiser site. There are two types of Cookies: Session cookies (which expire at the end of the browser session) and Persistent cookies (which stay on a user’s computer until deleted)

**What are we doing to comply with GDPR**

Campuscruiser has always taken privacy very seriously and has a strong commitment to protecting an individual’s data. We are engaged in the following initiatives for GDPR compliance:

  * Ensuring all employees fully understand GDPR
  * Documenting all systems and work flows that require personal data storage and update
  * Reviewing operating procedures and policies to ensure compliance by design for all future initiatives, gap analysis, and correction for areas requiring update
  * Updating contractual documentation to ensure our agreements with clients and other vendors are meeting GDPR compliance
  * Reviewing existing logging, monitoring, and tracking safeguards
  * Reviewing current privacy notices and terms of usage

Please contact your school for information regarding their privacy practices. Campuscruiser Privacy Policy is separate from their policy and does not control how they use any collected data. Campuscruiser is not responsible for your school’s collection, use, or disclosure of PII.

**Questions? Contact privacy@campuscruiser.com**
